Michael Rubenstein

460 Jensen Ave, Rahway, NJ 07065 | (732) 882-9239 | mrubenstein6192@gmail.com

My Portfolio: https://rubenstein-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ Github Profile: https://github.com/mrubenstein6192

Professional Summary

Experienced Mathematics Teacher seeking a change in career. Demonstrated history of building a positive rapport with students and faculty. After four years of experience in education and specialized knowledge in mathematics, looking to expand my horizons in the fields of mathematics, statistics, and web development.

Skills

Adaptability

Detail-Oriented

• Empathetic

- Fast Learner
- Motivated Team Player

Multitasking

Work History

Teacher Assistant, 06/2019 to Present

Trilogy Education Services: Rutgers Coding Bootcamp – Somerset, NJ

- Assisted instructor with daily tasks.
- Worked closely with students to reinforce various concepts.
- Provided students with the proper guidance to encourage self-sustainability.

Mathematics Teacher, 01/2015 to 01/2019

East Brunswick Public Schools - East Brunswick, NJ

- Planned and executed activities to promote student engagement, critical thinking, and the development of general knowledge in mathematics.
- Taught students Algebra 1, Algebra 2, Geometry, Precalculus, and Math for English as a Second Language Learners.
- Created and implemented an after-school professional development activity for school faculty members.
- Adviser for the Math Team, Jewish Student Union, and Sources of Strength.
- Coached one of the teams in the annual Powderpuff Flag Football game in 2017 and 2018.
- Met with parents to resolve conflicting educational priorities and issues.

Camp Counselor, 06/2013 to 08/2013

LakeView Day Camp – East Brunswick, NJ

- Collaborated with other camp counselors to create atmosphere of fun and learning.
- Implemented fun recreational activities, including swimming, boating, ceramics and dodgeball for a group of 30 children.
- Developed strong working relationships with campers, their parents and guardians, and other counselors through effective communication and active listening skills.
- Taught campers various skills, including how to safely start a campfire, how to rock climb and methods to avoid poisonous outdoor plants.
- Ensured proper supervision, safety, and security of all participants and assigned volunteers.

Sales Associate, 01/2012 to 04/2012

Kicks USA – Lawrenceville, NJ

- Collaborated with team to complete store maintenance, stocking, merchandising and upkeep.
- Prepared merchandise for distribution and placement across sales floor.
- Implemented up-selling strategies, encompassing recommendation of accessories and complementary purchases.
- Assisted customers in finding suitable products to meet their needs.

Education

Certificate of Completion, June 2019
Rutgers Coding Bootcamp – Somerset, NJ
Languages and Skills Learned:
HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Node.js, Responsive Desi

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Node.js, Responsive Design, Heroku, Git, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB.

Bachelor of Arts: Mathematics and Secondary Education, December 2014

The College Of New Jersey - Trenton, NJ